<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HopBot</title>
    <description>Decoding the beers of the Old Continent</description>
    <link>http://hopbot.eu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hopbot.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>International Affairs - The Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his formal life, he was the studio manager for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zXt56MB-3vc&quot;&gt;UB40&lt;/a&gt; the successful reggae-pop band that produced dozens of UK Top Singles. But when Nick first came to Croatia to enjoy the sun and the spoils of coastal Dalmatia, he found a new calling. When a seaside bar came on the market during his holiday he took the chance and signed the lease. This is how &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegarden.hr/brewery/en&quot;&gt;The Garden&lt;/a&gt; came to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-festival&quot;&gt;The Festival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colgan has resided in Zadar for the last 12 years, where he was instrumental in organising the hugely successful &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegarden.hr/the-garden-festival&quot;&gt;Garden Music Festival&lt;/a&gt;
And everybody knows what festivalgoers do - especially on a mid-summer beach event – they drink a hell of a lot beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“I am a fan of all crafts, especially beer”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years Nick and his partner David Plant was forced to sell one of the major Croatian beer brands at their events as nothing else was available in the country in that volume at the time. The partners often discussing this topic over a beer or two until Dave suggested they should make their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03044.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-to-brew&quot;&gt;Time to brew&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Mesopotamians could make it with primitive tools more than two millennia ago, how hard can it be really? But even though they both had immense love for the quality brews neither of them had any knowledge about beer production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“It's just hops, water and yeast!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cue Nick Calder-Scholes. In April 2016, the brewery’s business plan was coming along nicely. It was already settled that the location of the brewery will be in a warehouse in Zagreb, however the brewhouse was yet to be seen. Nick Calder-Scholes joined as head brewer and right away he had a great task, to kit out the whole brewery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03237.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Garden is the only brewery in Croatia where the lead brewer has previous commercial brewing experience. The Kiwi head-brewer was imported from the London based FourPure brewery where he gained the necessary experience to run a brewery that will become the primary supplier to several large-scale festivals in Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03241.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beer-and-the-local-economy&quot;&gt;Beer and the local economy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brewery is massive compared to most start-up beer ventures. The brewhouse has a 650 000 litre yearly theoretical throughput. Theoretical as the site has been only in production since May 2016, but that makes it even more impressive what this team have achieved in such short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick had the chance to hand pick the equipment that he would work on. He went with Letina to manufacture their tanks. They are a local Croatian company specialized in inox winery equipment. However, since they are only an hour drive away if anything goes pear shaped with their first commercial brewery equipment they are very fast to respond. This is a prime example how independent beer businesses can bring new life into the local economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;core-range&quot;&gt;Core range&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a country where euro-lagers are the go to beer it’s essential to have a beer on tap that would be easier to the palate.  Nick and his team of expat and Croatian brewers solved this task swiftly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Croatia already appreciates artisanal olive oil, wine and cheese, it is now time for beer”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their bridging beer is the Session Ale that is essentially what every festival beer should be – low alcohol but highly drinkable. In a country where national sports revolve around water you want something like this with you on the beach to cool down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03054.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I visited the taproom the Session Ale was not available on tap but I seized the opportunity to bring a couple of cans back with me. They are beautiful both inside and outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-dapper&quot;&gt;Looking dapper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is an integral part of the products. This just shows how much thought and craft goes into every drop. The graphics on the cans depict different scenes of Croatian scenery from woods to coastal rock formations. This brings home the point that even though the ingredients might come from all over the world this is a truly Croatian product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of design is also visible in the tap room. It’s industrial shell hides a cosy and friendly interior. No nonsense beer temple where the punters can consume great beer and the brewers can get direct feedback as they work away right behind the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03251.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reception&quot;&gt;Reception&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite beer in the range was the Citrus IPA. At 7.2% ABV I was expecting something of a full-bodied alcohol heavy beer. Instead I got a fruity, zesty, citrusy refreshing drink. According to Nick this is one of the top sellers from the core range along with the Stout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is quite fascinating and even surprised the brewers that in Croatia a stout that was released in the summer was sold out in a couple of weeks. Again, this is in a country where a couple of years ago you could only by mass produced euro lagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03037.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like the people are keen on trying tasty artisanal products after all and the bolder the taste the better. The Garden does cater to this demand and other than the core range they also release seasonal beers that would be considered interesting in any other countries as well. In the short year of operation, they have released 17 different limited edition beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03247.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were the first brewery to release sours in Croatia that has raised some eyebrows but overall had a great reception. As of today on Untappd one of their limited release sits at &lt;a href=&quot;https://untappd.com/beer/top_rated?country_id=35&quot;&gt;#5 on the top beer list&lt;/a&gt; of Croatian brews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03065.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Garden is definitely worth a visit if you’re in the area. Not only do they serve great beer, but there’s an excellent burger shack and occasionally the place turns into a music venue with DJs and probably the biggest disco ball of Central Europe. Surely the biggest in a brewery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In his formal life, he was the studio manager for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zXt56MB-3vc&quot;&gt;UB40&lt;/a&gt; the successful reggae-pop band that produced dozens of UK Top Singles. But when Nick first came to Croatia to enjoy the sun and the spoils of coastal Dalmatia, he found a new calling. When a seaside bar came on the market during his holiday he took the chance and signed the lease. This is how &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegarden.hr/brewery/en&quot;&gt;The Garden&lt;/a&gt; came to be.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/international-affairs-the-garden/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/international-affairs-the-garden/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Decoding Europe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Times have changed and so have I. It has been a couple of years since I abandoned beer blogging in the pursuit of a carreer. However I never stopped drinking beer and my professional path opened up new doors for me that I might be able to open further ajar and document it in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In  a nutshell I’m back in continental Europe whereas Britain seems to be moviong out of it. A lot has changed here since I left, a lot of new breweries, pubs and bottleshops sprung up in the &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt; wave of craft beer revolution. The only thing that seems to be stagnating is the reporting on the business in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for craft beer business news, release information and for general beer nerd content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Times have changed and so have I. It has been a couple of years since I abandoned beer blogging in the pursuit of a carreer. However I never stopped drinking beer and my professional path opened up new doors for me that I might be able to open further ajar and document it in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 20:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/decoding-europe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/decoding-europe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>I went to the Scottish Real Ale Festival</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotchwhiskyblog.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Hungarian Whisky Blog&lt;/a&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major Hungarian Whisky Blog but also one of the most knowledgeable bartenders in Edinburgh.  So obviously we went out to drink something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite happy coincidence that two interesting beer events were held the same time. As a sort of pre lash to the Scottish Real Ale Festival we managed to get our hands on a couple of tickets for the launch party of the much anticipated beer, the Mutiny on the Beagle by Natural Selection Brewing held on the 9th July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Selection is a group of ever changing students who’s task is to create and market a new beer every year. This year it was an all British IPA. The beer was served from both cask, keg and bottles. I managed to try the cask and the keg and I have to say I’m quite partial to the cask. It’s more complex and also gives back more real British ale vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the next day we headed to the Corn Exchange, and we managed to get there right when the gates opened. This meant we had time to see what’s available and quickly bought a couple of halfs from the beers we suspected will run out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know CAMRA had a fallout with Brewdog over their serving practices but it was a bit sad to be in the Scottish capital’s prime beer event without the most known craft brewery represented. Whereas Brewmeister beers were available, from a brewery who apparently falsified ABV data and scammed customers. I think CAMRA needs to think about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise the venue was great, organizers even provided an outside seating area, and because the weather was surprisingly good, that’s where we spent most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selection was superb, a lot of interesting brews come out of Scotland lately, probably thanks to the programs similar to Natural Selection. I had mostly some refreshing pale ales and bitters due to the weather, but I have to mention the Ola Dubh 12 Year Special Reserve from Harviestoun Brewery which made a lasting impression in me. Very complex taste, sweet and bitter and you can taste the wood it was matured in. That said this beer deserves a special occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will always remember the  Lapsang Souchong Tea Pot by Tin Pot too, but not in the good way. It tasted like BBQ sauce. This is the only thing i can remember about it. But this is what beer festivals are for, try beers you wouldn’t otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edinburgh, I’ll be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotchwhiskyblog.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Hungarian Whisky Blog&lt;/a&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major Hungarian Whisky Blog but also one of the most knowledgeable bartenders in Edinburgh.  So obviously we went out to drink something.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 19:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/i-went-to-the-scottish-real-ale-festival/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/i-went-to-the-scottish-real-ale-festival/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sandra Black IPA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I try not to read the labels before writing a review, so I’m no way influenced by the marketing team. Didn’t really work this time I had a glimpse of the label and now I’m unsure whether I can really taste gooseberries or I’m just imagining it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sandra is a well balanced beer, good carbonation, nice thick head, on the nose some malts, plum are quite noticeable. Tasewise As I mentioned I’d say gooseberry, redcurrant followed by a bit of roasted chestnut chocolate flavor. I can also feel a bit of floral aroma when I exhale but it’s masked by roastiness of the beer. If the alcohol content would be a bit lower I would call this sessionable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I try not to read the labels before writing a review, so I’m no way influenced by the marketing team. Didn’t really work this time I had a glimpse of the label and now I’m unsure whether I can really taste gooseberries or I’m just imagining it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/sandra-black-ipa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/sandra-black-ipa/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The attack of Haynau</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Spring of Nations took Europe by storm. People for various reasons from different background thought it was time to act. From Paris to Debrecen people fought for what they thought was right against their opressor, military officials like Julius Jacob von Haynau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1801 he started his military career in the Austrian army, rose quickly in the ranks and when the revolutionary insurrections of 1848 broke out in Italy, Haynau was selected to command troops to suppress them. He is still known as the “Hangman of Arad“, the “Hyena of Brescia” or just simply as “The Butcher” He had earned his delightful moniker by torturing prisoners and flogging women while suppressing revolts in Italy and Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But this is a beer blog, so why do I write all about this you ask? I get to it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austrians like their beer, and Haynau was no exception. There’s an urban legend about him enjoying a pint while watching the hanging of 13 Hungarian generals in Arad on 6th October 1849. Because of this in Hungary, people traditionally do not clink their glasses or mugs when drinking beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 1850 the Butcher decided to take a holiday in London, because even tyrants need a break every now and then. His visit wasn’t widely publicized he was just one of the many foreigners in the city. The sightseeing itinerary included a tour of Barclay and Perkins Brewery in Park Street, just off Southwark Bridge Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Down with the Austrian butcher!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brewery was considered one of the wonders of London for much of the 19th century and a must-visit destination for the serious traveler. Visitors included the Prince of Wales, the German statesman Otto von Bismarck, Prince Louis-Napoléon Bonaparte and Ibrahim Pasha of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haynau arrived to the brewery on 4th September with his nephew and his interpreter, trying to keep a low profile. Some sources say workers spied on his signature in the visitors book and this is how his cover was blown, but more likely his well known mustache gave him away. In the period reading was not as common as nowadays and around London every small stationer’s window had pictures representing him in the humane and gallant act of flogging women. He was a known figure of his time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, within minutes a posse of draymen (cart drivers who delivered beer from the brewery to the pubs) gathered, and as Haynou entered the stables, they lobbed a bale of hay at his head. And then began to pelt him with manure. Haynau and his company fled to the streets chased by lightermen and coalheavers tearing at his clothes, yanking out great tufts of his notorious long mustache. The mob had quickly swelled to more than 500 people, men and women alike, armed with whips and brooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desperate Haynau tried to hide in a room at the George Inn in Bankside, but was soon discovered and showered with yet more horse dung. By the time the police finally arrived, the pub was under siege and they had to rescue the general though the window and rowed him across the Thames to Somerset House guarantee his safety. The humiliated butcher was in no fit state to continue his holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letters congratulating the Barclay and Perkins dreyman arrived from workers’ associations as far afield as Paris and New York, and hundreds turned up for a huge celebration rally at Farringdon Hall. Not everyone was so enthusiastic about Haynou’s humiliation: Queen Victoria furiously condemned the mob, calling it a riot “got up by Hungarian refugees”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But to the working classes and many sections of the press, the Barclay and Perkins Draymen were heroes and defenders of female honor. Even Giuseppe Garibaldi visited the brewery later to congratulate the workers years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Barclay and Perkins brewery later was known as the Anchor, but in 1981 the brewery was demolished. Residential houses were erected on the site, but a commemorative plaque still reminds people of the international incident that happened in 1850. It’s definitely worth to take a walk there if you’re in London, The George Inn is still open to this day and there’s the Anchor pub near the brewery site, which used to be a brothel back then, but that’s a whole different story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The Spring of Nations took Europe by storm. People for various reasons from different background thought it was time to act. From Paris to Debrecen people fought for what they thought was right against their opressor, military officials like Julius Jacob von Haynau.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/the-attack-of-haynau/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/the-attack-of-haynau/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Secret Cellar Club – Pop-up Beer Festival in Cardiff</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;t looks like the age of the speakesay is back, but this time it’s serving alcohol across the pond and only for a day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just received a tweet, that for one day only on 3rd August, the Secret Cellar Club will open in an undisclosed location in Cardiff where local and unique cask ales will be served. Not much is known, but I’ll be there and report about the impromptu beer fest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get on the guest list either register for free or purchase an advanced ticket which includes drink vouchers and chance to win some beer related goodies. Visit the Secret Cellar Club website for more info or follow @PopUpBeer on twitter&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;t looks like the age of the speakesay is back, but this time it’s serving alcohol across the pond and only for a day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just received a tweet, that for one day only on 3rd August, the Secret Cellar Club will open in an undisclosed location in Cardiff where local and unique cask ales will be served. Not much is known, but I’ll be there and report about the impromptu beer fest.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/Secret-Cellar-Club-Pop-up-Beer-Festival-in-Cardiff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/Secret-Cellar-Club-Pop-up-Beer-Festival-in-Cardiff/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
