<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HopBot</title>
    <description>Decoding the beers of the Old Continent</description>
    <link>http://hopbot.eu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hopbot.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 08:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 08:03:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The boner beer story - Ah! Brew Works</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For starters, here’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://yeahyeah.eu&quot;&gt;Ah! Brew Works&lt;/a&gt;. A gypsy brewery operation from the Bulgarian capital Sofia. The city’s backdrop is the exact opposite of a beach holiday. It’s a mixture of brutalist concrete blocks and beautiful historical architecture. It’s intense and distracting so if one would like to market a beer it needs to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah! managed to do just that. They brewed one of the most potent beers I’ve ever tasted. It’s a beer brewed with mint and mursalski tea giving it a unique sweet herb flavor complemented by the bitterness of the hops. Mursalski tea is an herb long used by Rhodopean people, which are famous for their longevity and viability. The herb is also known as &lt;strong&gt;“Bulgarian Viagra”&lt;/strong&gt;, hence the nickname for Ah! no7 - Boner Beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beer is the brainchild of &lt;strong&gt;Rory Miller&lt;/strong&gt;, the Seattle born co-founder and brewer. Since this is such an interesting concept I asked Rory to tell everything about beer, business and boners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whose-idea-was-the-brewery-and-how-did-it-all-evolve-to-the-current-state&quot;&gt;Whose idea was the brewery and how did it all evolve to the current state?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started this whole thing six years ago with another brand. We have organized the first craft beer fest here in Bulgaria - it was maybe even the first in the Balkans - called &lt;em&gt;“Rhythm and Beer”.&lt;/em&gt; It sparked the local beer culture and now we have some sort of craft beer scene although it’s still in it’s infancy. I and my partner worked hard and relentlessly to educate people and build a base which we now see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Craft beers were taken over by soulless moneymen and wannabe mafia monkeys&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to when we first began - no craft, no macro, no nothing – we reached a point where craft production is over -flourishing. Unfortunately, a few of the craft beers were taken over by soulless moneymen and wannabe mafia monkeys who think you are part of the scene because you have grungy long hair and a shabby beard. Their only goal is profit and they run these so-called brands accordingly. This is from personal experience. We were the founders of a couple of these ventures but later left due to creative and personal conflicts. It’s embarrassing. However, all bad things eventually are remedied, they too will soon taste our medicine. There still are those of us dedicated to the evolution of craft beer culture and it’s laws of creativity, loyalty, passion and innovation. And we will prevail!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-you-think-bulgaria-is-going-through-a-craft-beer-revolution-what-does-it-look-like-from-the-inside&quot;&gt;Do you think Bulgaria is going through a craft beer revolution? What does it look like from the inside?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bulgaria is definitely a newcomer to the craft beer revolution, which we are proud to have ignited. As in all revolutions those who are true to the cause will shine and those who are just counting their coins and exploiting the public will fall away into the dust from which they came. They have no idea of the strength and passion of those who have dedicated everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ah.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are seeing an influx of producers both brick and mortar as well as gypsy brewers - like ourselves. We have had many discussions with colleagues in Serbia, for example, and this influx is not really the best thing in our opinion.  It’s like having 10 choices of the same soda. It hurts everybody. The market is still young and very small so there is not much room for massive competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before people dive into brewing just because they like beer, first they should educate those around them, spread the culture of craft beer thus increasing the market. Otherwise it’s just a recipe for failure and most start up breweries will fail after one year without a strong base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-inspired-the-beers-in-your-core-range&quot;&gt;What inspired the beers in your core range?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial idea behind our recipes was simple – Be different. We want to take typical recipes, typical styles and add to them crazy, new stuff. We never want to build our company on typical recipes. Why brew an IPA when there are a 1000 fantastic IPAs out there already? Nothing new, nothing interesting for us there. So, we want to make weird shit and good shit at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;We want to make weird shit and good shit at the same time!&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boner Beer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or Mursasalski Red or Number 7 was to use local ingredients and to use special ingredients - never before used in this way. Mursalski tea is something the Bulgarians are proud to have and we wanted to channel their pride and show them a new way to enjoy their favourite herb. It took us a while to perfect the recipe because the ingredients have never been used before and the process that I wanted to use them was also a new one… but after a couple failures we finally balanced our, now, best known beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our other core beer was more of an economical choice and basically a base beer that we could always alter if we wanted - Bulgarian Pale Ale or Number 3. A basic pale ale that people could drink easily without pretence. A sort of stepping stone to the strange and provocative world of craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-there-any-new-beers-in-the-pipeline&quot;&gt;Are there any new beers in the pipeline?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we plan to release 3 to 4 new recipes as we have been a bit stagnant recently, experimenting and never quite satisfied with what we came up with. We are happy to say we have finally came up with a few very solid recipes and new packaging which we are very excited to release this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ah.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-had-the-pleasure-to-taste-mursasalski-red-and-i-loved-the-complex-flavor-profile-is-this-the-craziest-recipe-youve-ever-came-up-with&quot;&gt;I had the pleasure to taste Mursasalski Red and I loved the complex flavor profile. Is this the craziest recipe you’ve ever came up with?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this recipe. It’s my baby. It’s not the craziest recipe I have come up with but it &lt;u&gt;IS&lt;/u&gt; the craziest recipe that against all odds works so well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beer-brewing-is-inherently-an-international-affair-the-best-ingredients-frequently-travel-across-half-the-globe-do-you-use-any-local-ingredients&quot;&gt;Beer brewing is inherently an international affair. The best ingredients frequently travel across half the globe. Do you use any local ingredients?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a gypsy, contract, nomadic brewery so we brew in other countries for our local market. It was very important for us to use as much as possible local ingredients to try and keep the beer as Bulgarian as possible. This ensures that we help the local industries at the same time. In all our beers, we have Bulgarian ingredients. So far, we use &lt;strong&gt;Mursalski tea, mint, hops, Goji Berries and thyme - all from Bulgaria&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-sets-ah-apart-from-other-local-breweries&quot;&gt;What sets Ah! apart from other local breweries?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well if we speak about the macro breweries, I feel we are different because we try to be really involved with the public. We conduct a craft beer education program and constantly organise and participate in innovative and intriguing events. We are also very dedicated to helping local artists by giving them a platform with our label, constantly changing the artist we collaborate with and helping them financially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;nbsp;It's not just beer, it's attitude and soul that we sell&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big difference is that for us it’s not just beer, it’s &lt;strong&gt;attitude and soul&lt;/strong&gt; that we sell. For us brand is just as important as the product itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your design is bold, contemporary and fun. Is there a connection between the packaging and the beer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Ah is an infinite exhibition&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. We definitely take brand awareness and recognition very seriously. Ah is an infinite exhibition applied to a product. We use an ever-changing artwork on all our beer labels and every time another local artist has the chance to design it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-you-find-your-customers-how-do-you-distribute&quot;&gt;How did you find your customers? How do you distribute?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We obviously attract the craft beer crowd but we also try to attract new prospective customers with events, PR campaigns and communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, our favourite way is still just to notice a cool place and go in to talk with the managers, employees and their customers about our beer. We distribute ourselves and through a few local distributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-would-love-to-drink-no7-more-often-any-plans-to-export&quot;&gt;I would love to drink no7 more often. Any plans to export?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We would love to be able to supply your love! **We hope this year we will start selling outside of Bulgaria especially the number 7 beer. We would like to begin in the neighbouring countries as well as a couple western European spots like **Spain, Italy, Germany and France&lt;/strong&gt; if all goes well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-plans-for-the-future&quot;&gt;Any plans for the future?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to focus on the brand and make it as strong as possible while also releasing a few new interesting recipes for beers. We are also planning to expand our product range by including &lt;em&gt;more than just beer&lt;/em&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For starters, here’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://yeahyeah.eu&quot;&gt;Ah! Brew Works&lt;/a&gt;. A gypsy brewery operation from the Bulgarian capital Sofia. The city’s backdrop is the exact opposite of a beach holiday. It’s a mixture of brutalist concrete blocks and beautiful historical architecture. It’s intense and distracting so if one would like to market a beer it needs to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/the-boner-beer-story-ah-brew-works/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/the-boner-beer-story-ah-brew-works/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>International Affairs - The Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his formal life, he was the studio manager for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zXt56MB-3vc&quot;&gt;UB40&lt;/a&gt; the successful reggae-pop band that produced dozens of UK Top Singles. But when Nick first came to Croatia to enjoy the sun and the spoils of coastal Dalmatia, he found a new calling. When a seaside bar came on the market during his holiday he took the chance and signed the lease. This is how &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegarden.hr/brewery/en&quot;&gt;The Garden&lt;/a&gt; came to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-festival&quot;&gt;The Festival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colgan has resided in Zadar for the last 12 years, where he was instrumental in organising the hugely successful &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegarden.hr/the-garden-festival&quot;&gt;Garden Music Festival&lt;/a&gt;
And everybody knows what festivalgoers do - especially on a mid-summer beach event – they drink a hell of a lot beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“I am a fan of all crafts, especially beer”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years Nick and his partner David Plant was forced to sell one of the major Croatian beer brands at their events as nothing else was available in the country in that volume at the time. The partners often discussing this topic over a beer or two until Dave suggested they should make their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03044.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-to-brew&quot;&gt;Time to brew&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Mesopotamians could make it with primitive tools more than two millennia ago, how hard can it be really? But even though they both had immense love for the quality brews neither of them had any knowledge about beer production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“It's just hops, water and yeast!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cue Nick Calder-Scholes. In April 2016, the brewery’s business plan was coming along nicely. It was already settled that the location of the brewery will be in a warehouse in Zagreb, however the brewhouse was yet to be seen. Nick Calder-Scholes joined as head brewer and right away he had a great task, to kit out the whole brewery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03237.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Garden is the only brewery in Croatia where the lead brewer has previous commercial brewing experience. The Kiwi head-brewer was imported from the London based FourPure brewery where he gained the necessary experience to run a brewery that will become the primary supplier to several large-scale festivals in Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03241.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beer-and-the-local-economy&quot;&gt;Beer and the local economy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brewery is massive compared to most start-up beer ventures. The brewhouse has a 650 000 litre yearly theoretical throughput. Theoretical as the site has been only in production since May 2016, but that makes it even more impressive what this team have achieved in such short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick had the chance to hand pick the equipment that he would work on. He went with Letina to manufacture their tanks. They are a local Croatian company specialized in inox winery equipment. However, since they are only an hour drive away if anything goes pear shaped with their first commercial brewery equipment they are very fast to respond. This is a prime example how independent beer businesses can bring new life into the local economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;core-range&quot;&gt;Core range&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a country where euro-lagers are the go to beer it’s essential to have a beer on tap that would be easier to the palate.  Nick and his team of expat and Croatian brewers solved this task swiftly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Croatia already appreciates artisanal olive oil, wine and cheese, it is now time for beer”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their bridging beer is the Session Ale that is essentially what every festival beer should be – low alcohol but highly drinkable. In a country where national sports revolve around water you want something like this with you on the beach to cool down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03054.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I visited the taproom the Session Ale was not available on tap but I seized the opportunity to bring a couple of cans back with me. They are beautiful both inside and outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-dapper&quot;&gt;Looking dapper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is an integral part of the products. This just shows how much thought and craft goes into every drop. The graphics on the cans depict different scenes of Croatian scenery from woods to coastal rock formations. This brings home the point that even though the ingredients might come from all over the world this is a truly Croatian product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of design is also visible in the tap room. It’s industrial shell hides a cosy and friendly interior. No nonsense beer temple where the punters can consume great beer and the brewers can get direct feedback as they work away right behind the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03251.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reception&quot;&gt;Reception&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite beer in the range was the Citrus IPA. At 7.2% ABV I was expecting something of a full-bodied alcohol heavy beer. Instead I got a fruity, zesty, citrusy refreshing drink. According to Nick this is one of the top sellers from the core range along with the Stout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is quite fascinating and even surprised the brewers that in Croatia a stout that was released in the summer was sold out in a couple of weeks. Again, this is in a country where a couple of years ago you could only by mass produced euro lagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03037.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like the people are keen on trying tasty artisanal products after all and the bolder the taste the better. The Garden does cater to this demand and other than the core range they also release seasonal beers that would be considered interesting in any other countries as well. In the short year of operation, they have released 17 different limited edition beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03247.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were the first brewery to release sours in Croatia that has raised some eyebrows but overall had a great reception. As of today on Untappd one of their limited release sits at &lt;a href=&quot;https://untappd.com/beer/top_rated?country_id=35&quot;&gt;#5 on the top beer list&lt;/a&gt; of Croatian brews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DSC03065.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Garden is definitely worth a visit if you’re in the area. Not only do they serve great beer, but there’s an excellent burger shack and occasionally the place turns into a music venue with DJs and probably the biggest disco ball of Central Europe. Surely the biggest in a brewery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In his formal life, he was the studio manager for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zXt56MB-3vc&quot;&gt;UB40&lt;/a&gt; the successful reggae-pop band that produced dozens of UK Top Singles. But when Nick first came to Croatia to enjoy the sun and the spoils of coastal Dalmatia, he found a new calling. When a seaside bar came on the market during his holiday he took the chance and signed the lease. This is how &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegarden.hr/brewery/en&quot;&gt;The Garden&lt;/a&gt; came to be.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/international-affairs-the-garden/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/international-affairs-the-garden/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Decoding Europe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Times have changed and so have I. It has been a couple of years since I abandoned beer blogging in the pursuit of a carreer. However I never stopped drinking beer and my professional path opened up new doors for me that I might be able to open further ajar and document it in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In  a nutshell I’m back in continental Europe whereas Britain seems to be moviong out of it. A lot has changed here since I left, a lot of new breweries, pubs and bottleshops sprung up in the &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt; wave of craft beer revolution. The only thing that seems to be stagnating is the reporting on the business in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for craft beer business news, release information and for general beer nerd content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Times have changed and so have I. It has been a couple of years since I abandoned beer blogging in the pursuit of a carreer. However I never stopped drinking beer and my professional path opened up new doors for me that I might be able to open further ajar and document it in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 20:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/decoding-europe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/decoding-europe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>I went to the Scottish Real Ale Festival</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotchwhiskyblog.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Hungarian Whisky Blog&lt;/a&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major Hungarian Whisky Blog but also one of the most knowledgeable bartenders in Edinburgh.  So obviously we went out to drink something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite happy coincidence that two interesting beer events were held the same time. As a sort of pre lash to the Scottish Real Ale Festival we managed to get our hands on a couple of tickets for the launch party of the much anticipated beer, the Mutiny on the Beagle by Natural Selection Brewing held on the 9th July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Selection is a group of ever changing students who’s task is to create and market a new beer every year. This year it was an all British IPA. The beer was served from both cask, keg and bottles. I managed to try the cask and the keg and I have to say I’m quite partial to the cask. It’s more complex and also gives back more real British ale vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the next day we headed to the Corn Exchange, and we managed to get there right when the gates opened. This meant we had time to see what’s available and quickly bought a couple of halfs from the beers we suspected will run out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know CAMRA had a fallout with Brewdog over their serving practices but it was a bit sad to be in the Scottish capital’s prime beer event without the most known craft brewery represented. Whereas Brewmeister beers were available, from a brewery who apparently falsified ABV data and scammed customers. I think CAMRA needs to think about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise the venue was great, organizers even provided an outside seating area, and because the weather was surprisingly good, that’s where we spent most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selection was superb, a lot of interesting brews come out of Scotland lately, probably thanks to the programs similar to Natural Selection. I had mostly some refreshing pale ales and bitters due to the weather, but I have to mention the Ola Dubh 12 Year Special Reserve from Harviestoun Brewery which made a lasting impression in me. Very complex taste, sweet and bitter and you can taste the wood it was matured in. That said this beer deserves a special occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will always remember the  Lapsang Souchong Tea Pot by Tin Pot too, but not in the good way. It tasted like BBQ sauce. This is the only thing i can remember about it. But this is what beer festivals are for, try beers you wouldn’t otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edinburgh, I’ll be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major &lt;a href=&quot;https://scotchwhiskyblog.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Hungarian Whisky Blog&lt;/a&gt;This actually happened a good two weeks ago, when I was visiting my good old friend Norbi. He’ not only the author of the major Hungarian Whisky Blog but also one of the most knowledgeable bartenders in Edinburgh.  So obviously we went out to drink something.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 19:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/i-went-to-the-scottish-real-ale-festival/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/i-went-to-the-scottish-real-ale-festival/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sandra Black IPA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I try not to read the labels before writing a review, so I’m no way influenced by the marketing team. Didn’t really work this time I had a glimpse of the label and now I’m unsure whether I can really taste gooseberries or I’m just imagining it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sandra is a well balanced beer, good carbonation, nice thick head, on the nose some malts, plum are quite noticeable. Tasewise As I mentioned I’d say gooseberry, redcurrant followed by a bit of roasted chestnut chocolate flavor. I can also feel a bit of floral aroma when I exhale but it’s masked by roastiness of the beer. If the alcohol content would be a bit lower I would call this sessionable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I try not to read the labels before writing a review, so I’m no way influenced by the marketing team. Didn’t really work this time I had a glimpse of the label and now I’m unsure whether I can really taste gooseberries or I’m just imagining it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/sandra-black-ipa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/sandra-black-ipa/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The attack of Haynau</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Spring of Nations took Europe by storm. People for various reasons from different background thought it was time to act. From Paris to Debrecen people fought for what they thought was right against their opressor, military officials like Julius Jacob von Haynau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1801 he started his military career in the Austrian army, rose quickly in the ranks and when the revolutionary insurrections of 1848 broke out in Italy, Haynau was selected to command troops to suppress them. He is still known as the “Hangman of Arad“, the “Hyena of Brescia” or just simply as “The Butcher” He had earned his delightful moniker by torturing prisoners and flogging women while suppressing revolts in Italy and Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But this is a beer blog, so why do I write all about this you ask? I get to it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austrians like their beer, and Haynau was no exception. There’s an urban legend about him enjoying a pint while watching the hanging of 13 Hungarian generals in Arad on 6th October 1849. Because of this in Hungary, people traditionally do not clink their glasses or mugs when drinking beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 1850 the Butcher decided to take a holiday in London, because even tyrants need a break every now and then. His visit wasn’t widely publicized he was just one of the many foreigners in the city. The sightseeing itinerary included a tour of Barclay and Perkins Brewery in Park Street, just off Southwark Bridge Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Down with the Austrian butcher!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brewery was considered one of the wonders of London for much of the 19th century and a must-visit destination for the serious traveler. Visitors included the Prince of Wales, the German statesman Otto von Bismarck, Prince Louis-Napoléon Bonaparte and Ibrahim Pasha of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haynau arrived to the brewery on 4th September with his nephew and his interpreter, trying to keep a low profile. Some sources say workers spied on his signature in the visitors book and this is how his cover was blown, but more likely his well known mustache gave him away. In the period reading was not as common as nowadays and around London every small stationer’s window had pictures representing him in the humane and gallant act of flogging women. He was a known figure of his time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, within minutes a posse of draymen (cart drivers who delivered beer from the brewery to the pubs) gathered, and as Haynou entered the stables, they lobbed a bale of hay at his head. And then began to pelt him with manure. Haynau and his company fled to the streets chased by lightermen and coalheavers tearing at his clothes, yanking out great tufts of his notorious long mustache. The mob had quickly swelled to more than 500 people, men and women alike, armed with whips and brooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desperate Haynau tried to hide in a room at the George Inn in Bankside, but was soon discovered and showered with yet more horse dung. By the time the police finally arrived, the pub was under siege and they had to rescue the general though the window and rowed him across the Thames to Somerset House guarantee his safety. The humiliated butcher was in no fit state to continue his holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letters congratulating the Barclay and Perkins dreyman arrived from workers’ associations as far afield as Paris and New York, and hundreds turned up for a huge celebration rally at Farringdon Hall. Not everyone was so enthusiastic about Haynou’s humiliation: Queen Victoria furiously condemned the mob, calling it a riot “got up by Hungarian refugees”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But to the working classes and many sections of the press, the Barclay and Perkins Draymen were heroes and defenders of female honor. Even Giuseppe Garibaldi visited the brewery later to congratulate the workers years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Barclay and Perkins brewery later was known as the Anchor, but in 1981 the brewery was demolished. Residential houses were erected on the site, but a commemorative plaque still reminds people of the international incident that happened in 1850. It’s definitely worth to take a walk there if you’re in London, The George Inn is still open to this day and there’s the Anchor pub near the brewery site, which used to be a brothel back then, but that’s a whole different story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The Spring of Nations took Europe by storm. People for various reasons from different background thought it was time to act. From Paris to Debrecen people fought for what they thought was right against their opressor, military officials like Julius Jacob von Haynau.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/the-attack-of-haynau/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/the-attack-of-haynau/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Secret Cellar Club – Pop-up Beer Festival in Cardiff</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;t looks like the age of the speakesay is back, but this time it’s serving alcohol across the pond and only for a day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just received a tweet, that for one day only on 3rd August, the Secret Cellar Club will open in an undisclosed location in Cardiff where local and unique cask ales will be served. Not much is known, but I’ll be there and report about the impromptu beer fest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get on the guest list either register for free or purchase an advanced ticket which includes drink vouchers and chance to win some beer related goodies. Visit the Secret Cellar Club website for more info or follow @PopUpBeer on twitter&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;t looks like the age of the speakesay is back, but this time it’s serving alcohol across the pond and only for a day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just received a tweet, that for one day only on 3rd August, the Secret Cellar Club will open in an undisclosed location in Cardiff where local and unique cask ales will be served. Not much is known, but I’ll be there and report about the impromptu beer fest.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/stories/Secret-Cellar-Club-Pop-up-Beer-Festival-in-Cardiff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/stories/Secret-Cellar-Club-Pop-up-Beer-Festival-in-Cardiff/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
