<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HopBot</title>
    <description>Decoding the beers of the Old Continent</description>
    <link>http://hopbot.eu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hopbot.eu/feed-framerate.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 12:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 12:53:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ver.1</title>
        <description>
</description>
        
          <description>
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ver.2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brussels has no shortage of bars and pubs where one can enjoy some traditional Belgian beers. There’s no need for any guides or maps to find a quiet place to enjoy a brew with locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strolling around on the cobblestone covered streets we have stumbled upont the &lt;strong&gt;Au Bon Vieux Temps&lt;/strong&gt; bar near Saint Niclas church. The bar itself is like a cathedral to beer complete with chandaliers and stained glass windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short of drinking a beer in an actual monastery this is the best way to enjoy an abbey ale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Brussels has no shortage of bars and pubs where one can enjoy some traditional Belgian beers. There’s no need for any guides or maps to find a quiet place to enjoy a brew with locals.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ver.3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spotted in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-2/&quot;&gt;Au Bon Vieux Temps&lt;/a&gt;  this magnificient creature guards the stock so we can enjoy a rodent free pint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Spotted in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-2/&quot;&gt;Au Bon Vieux Temps&lt;/a&gt;  this magnificient creature guards the stock so we can enjoy a rodent free pint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-3/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ver.4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ordre-manneken-pis.wikeo.be/&quot;&gt;Ordre des Amis de Manneken-Pis&lt;/a&gt; plays the trumpet while enjoying a pint of &lt;em&gt;Palm&lt;/em&gt; in front of the famous statue depicting a urinating toddler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ordre-manneken-pis.wikeo.be/&quot;&gt;Ordre des Amis de Manneken-Pis&lt;/a&gt; plays the trumpet while enjoying a pint of &lt;em&gt;Palm&lt;/em&gt; in front of the famous statue depicting a urinating toddler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-4/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ver.5</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The only reason for my visit to Bratislavský Meštiansky Pivovar in Bratislava was that I was hungry. My significant other already scouted the place online. I was told it has a special BBQ spare ribs on the menu and I had time to devour it. I knew it is also a brewery but that was secondary to the ribs. That all changed when I had my first sip of their dark house beer just before the gigantic portion of food arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While eating the meat we noticed a sweet smell. That was the indistinguishable smell of cooked malted barley. A smell every brewer and homebrewer alike notices immediately. That meant that somewhere in the house there’s beer being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we finished our meal I asked our waiter if I could take a photo of the kettles, just for the novelty of it. He was at first surprised of the request, but then he lead me to the manager. The manager guided us down several flights of stairs to meet a grey haired but joyful middle aged man. Without any introduction he told me to just go and take photos of anything I want, pointing at the beautiful copper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;He only spoke Slovakian and a bit of broken German, but I knew what he was talking about. The love for his craft was unmistakable. He started to talk about the beer, the kettles and the brewery. Then guided us to the fermentation tanks to sample some of the local brews he was working on. Altough neither me or my girlfriend speak Slovakian, we understood everything. Passion speaks louder than words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The only reason for my visit to Bratislavský Meštiansky Pivovar in Bratislava was that I was hungry. My significant other already scouted the place online. I was told it has a special BBQ spare ribs on the menu and I had time to devour it. I knew it is also a brewery but that was secondary to the ribs. That all changed when I had my first sip of their dark house beer just before the gigantic portion of food arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 09:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hopbot.eu/framerate/ver-5/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
